Guide to the Duke University Libraries Collection of Haggadot, 1200-2003 (bulk1900-2003)
Duke University Libraries Collection of Haggadot 1200-2003 (bulk 1900-2003
- Date List Series, 1200-2003
  - 1950-1959 Subseries, (62 items)
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 195-?., 24 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew with non-traditional text. Includes a form for admittance into the hospital with a handwritten note on the back. This Haggadah was written and Illustrated by Gidon Katsch.
    - The book of Passover; Passover in life and literature and Haggadah, 195-?., 16 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Illustrations by Siegmund Forst. Jewish Pocket Books published haggadah which includes a number of essays about Passover in Life and Literature. Printed as a fundraising tool for Yeshivah Torah Vodaath and Mesifta with a request for money in Yiddish and English.
  - 1960-1969 Subseries, (52 items)
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1960., 27 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew essays about the history of the Haggadah. On verso of t.p.: The Passover Haggadah: its sources and history, with the complete text of the traditional Haggadah, the most ancient Haggadah from the Cairo Genizah and sample pages of manuscript and printed Haggadot in reproduction. By Ernst Daniel Goldschmidt.
    - Hagadah shelemah, 1960., 26 cm. Text only.
      Includes commentaries by Menahem Kasher and Shmuel Ashkenazi.
    - The John Rylands Haggadah / Cecil Roth, 1960., 25 cm. Resource Material.
      Location: Manchester, England
      Article about the John Rylands Haggadah by Cecil Roth. Reprinted from the Bulletin of the John Rylands Library, Vol. 43, No. 1, September, 1960.
    - The first known printed Passover Hagadah / by Gershom Kohen, 1960., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Reprint of Prague, 1527 ed. Photo-copy of Hebrew text with English translation in parallel columns. Fundraising tool for the Orphan Hospital Ward of Israel. Duke has two copies of this Haggadah.
    - The Passover Haggadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah] / with a new translation by Saadyah Maximon and illustrations by Paul K. Freeman, 1960., 16 cm. Illustrated.
      Fundraising tool for the Orphans' Home for Girls in Israel.
    - The Passover Haggadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah] / with a new translation by Saadyah Maximon and illustrations by Paul K. Freeman, 1960., 16 cm. Illustrated.
      Fundraising tool for the Jerusalem General Israel Orphans' Home for Girls.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah] = From twilight to dawn, the traditional Pessach Hagadah / arranged by Rabbi Shlomo Kahn, 1960., 24 cm. Text only.
      Text in English and Hebrew on opposite pages; commentary in English.
    - Bibliografyah shel hagadot Pesah mi-reshit ha-defus ve-`ad ha-yom be-tseruf `esrim ve-hamishah tsilume dapim mi-tokh hagadot yikrot-metsi'ut, 1960., 35 cm. Illustrated.
      By Abraham Yaari. Bibliography of the Passover Haggadah from the earliest printed edition to 1900 with twenty five reproductions from rare editions.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Passover Haggadah / with a new translation by Saadyah Maximon; and illustrations by Paul K. Freeman, 1960., 16 cm. Illustrated.
      Printed as a fundraising tool for the General Israel Orphans' Home for Girls. Duke has three copies of this Haggadah.
    - Bibliografyah shel hagadot Pesah mi-reshit ha-defus ve-`ad ha-yom be-tseruf `esrim ve-hamishah tsilume dapim mi-tokh hagadot yikrot-metsi'ut, 1960., 35 cm. Illustrated.
    - Haggadah for Passover. Copied and illustrated by Ben Shahn. With a translation, introd., and historical notes by Cecil Roth, 1960., 31 cm. Illustrated.
    - Offenbacher Haggadah, 1960., 27 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Flushing, New York
      Hebrew and German.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1961., 28 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew text with some ceremonial directions in English and French. Illustrations by Moshe Proops.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1961., 19 cm. Illustrated.
      Includes 34 illustrations by Ze'ev Raban.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah: first printed edition of a Haggadah from a parchment manuscript of the early eighteenth Century, anno 1731, Hamburg ... / courtesy of New York Public library - Jewish Division, 1961., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Printed as a fundraising tool. Hebrew introduction with an English summary of the introduction.
    - The Haggadah of Passover: Illustrated by David Gilboa, 1961?., 24 cm. Illustrated.
      Text in Hebrew with ceremonial directions in English and Hebrew. Sueded blue cloth binding with blue enameled metal title label on front cover.
    - Hagadah for Passover = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1961-1962., 17 cm. Illustrated.
      Printed as an advertising tool for the Streit Matzo Company.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1962., 23 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Handwritten and illustrated by Arthur Szyk.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1962., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Arranged by Walter Orenstein for a children's service. Includes explanations for difficult words as well as questions and answers about the laws of Passover.
    - A Haggadah for our time / edited and arranged by Rose Bernard; illustrated by Florence Sloat, 1962., 14 x 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Los Angeles, California
      Non-traditional text with music. Intended for children.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: ketav-yad me-osef Baron David Gintsburg ha-nimtsa be-Sifriyah ha-le'umit be-Moskva = The Günzburg Haggadah: first printed edition of an illuminated manuscript from the USSR microfilm collection in the New York University Library of Judaica and Hebraica, 1962., 23 cm. Illustrated.
      Printed as a fundraising tool. Hebrew introduction with an English summary of the introduction. Original from 1725.
    - The passover haggadah: a new version / by Israel Chodos; music edited by Carl Urstein; ill. by Thelma Witmer. Los Angeles: D'ror Press, 1962, 1962., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Original text with traditional elements.
    - Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah / translated by Rabbi Z. Harry Gutstein, 1963., 23 cm. Illustrated.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah] = The Haggadah of Passover / edited by Rabbi David and Tamar de Sola Pool, 1963., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Cecil Roth Oxford Haggadah: written in 1753 and subsequently owned by Joseph b. Leizer Speier of Amsterdam, 1963., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Fundraising tool for the Orphan Hospital Ward of Israel. Duke has two copies of this Haggadah.
    - Haggadah for the American family: [a complete new Seder service: English service with directions / written by Martin Berkowitz], 1963., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Second printing of the Haggadah for the American Family (1963). Includes the complete traditional Hebrew seder text as well as a shortened Hebrew/English text. Center pages contain an advertisement for Standard Brands Incorporated.
    - Hagadah li-yeladim = The children's Haggadah / edited by A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Erwin Singer; with a new translation in prose and verse by Isidore Wartski and Arthur Saul Super; and with a selection of Seder melodies, 1963., 30 cm. Illustrated.
      Several illustrations have movable parts. Includes songs for voices, chiefly unaccompanied.
    - Ta`arukhat Hagadot-Pesh me-osfo R. Natan Stayner .., 1964., 17 cm. Illustrated.
      Program for an exhibition of Pesach-Haggadoth from the private collection of Mr. Nathan Steiner at the Museum of Ethnography and Folklore in Tel Aviv. In Hebrew.
    - Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1964., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Printed by General Foods Corporation as an advertisement for their Maxwell House brand of coffee.
    - The Pessach Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1964., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Armentières-en-Brie, France
      Fundraising tool for Yeshivah Ohr Joseph in France. Hebrew and English. Illustrated by Roland Blum. Duke has two copies of this Haggadah.
    - Pardes ha-Hagadah: Hagadah shel Pesah / perushim ... remazim ... dinim ... sipure yetsi'at Mitsraim ba-`arikhat Gedalyah Segal be-siyua` 'Elimelekh He`shin, 1964-1965., 25 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew only. Includes commentaries.
    - Hagadah, 1965., 24 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Newly translated throughout, with an introduction, by Harold Fisch -- T.p. verso.
    - The Haggadah: past and present, 1965., 27 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Cincinatti, Ohio
      Volume VII of the Journal Studies in Bibliography and Booklore. A number of articles about Haggadot in Hebrew and English.
    - Passover Haggadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah (romanized form)], 1965., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: ketav yad metsuyar `al Klaf me-Osef Sifriyat Bet ha-nivharim be-Vashington mi-shenat...1470 = The Washington Haggadah: first printed edition of an illuminated manuscript from the Library of Congress.., 1965., 14 x 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Printed as a fundraising tool. Preface in English and Hebrew by L. Marwick. Reproduction of the Washington Haggadah from 1470. Original written by Joel ben Simeon. Duke has two copies of this Haggadah.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / targum angli hadash me-et Betsal'el Rot; `arikhah Beno Rotenberg; mavo Mikha'el Avi-Yonah = The Passover Haggadah / a new English version by Cecil Roth; edited by Beno Rothenberg; introduction by Michael Avi-Yonah, 1965., 31 cm. Illustrated.
      Haggadah contains photographs of the landscape and antiquities of Israel and her neighbors as well as photographs of ornamented utensils used for the Passover Holiday from previous centuries and housed at the Bezalel Jewish National Museum in Jerusalem. The English translation is by Prof. Cecil Roth and the introduction is by Prof. Michael Avi-Yonah. The first Hebrew map, an etching by Abraham bar Yacob, originally printed in the Amsterdam Hagaddah of 1695, on lining papers.
    - The Gospel of Mark: the new Christian Jewish Passover Haggadah, 1965., 25 cm. Text only.
      Location: Leiden, Netherlands
    - Passover Haggadah = [Hagadah shel Pesah]: a faithful English rendering / by Abraham Regelson; illustrated by Siegmund Forst, 1966., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Printed as a fundraising tool for the Home of the Sages of Israel.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / he`etik u-tsayar Benyamin Sha'n; `im targum, mavo, u-he'arot me-et Betsalel Rot, 1966., 40 cm
      Title on added t.p.: Haggadah for Passover. Hebrew t.p. dated 724 i. e. 1963 or 1964. One of 228 numbered copies.
    - Haggadah for the American family: English service with directions / written by Martin Berkowitz, 1966., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Miami, Florida
      Traditional Hebrew text with a shortened English/Hebrew seder printed in the direction of an English book (left to right). Of special note are the kosher food ads found on the inside covers of the Haggadah as well as the center pages which divide the English from the Hebrew sections. The advertisements found on the center pages are clearly identified as being for foods which, while kosher, are not kosher for Passover.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah mi-tokh mahazor Roma = The Mahzor Roma Haggadah: Bologna, Italy, anno 1540 / from the copy at the New York Public Library, Jewish Division, 1966., 22 cm. Text only.
      Fundraising tool for the Orphan Hospital Ward of Israel. Reproduction of the Mahzor Roma Haggadah. Hebrew text with commentary in Rashi script. Duke has two copies of this Haggadah.
    - [Hagadat Yehude Sin] = The Haggadah of the Chinese Jews: first printed edition from a manuscript of the seventeenth-eighteenth Century C.E. originating in the Jewish colony of K'ai-Feng Fu / with an introduction by Prof. Cecil Roth, 1967., 22 cm. Text only.
      Fundraising tool for the Orphan Hospital Ward of Israel. Hebrew text with an English introduction. Missing Dayyenu and some other traditional elements; includes hymns not found in the traditional text. Incorrect vocalization at times. Ceremonial directions written in the Judeo-Persian language, but using Hebrew characters.
    - [Hagadat Yehude Sin] = The Haggadah of the Chinese Jews: first printed edition from a manuscript of the seventeenth-eighteenth Century C.E. originating in the Jewish colony of K'ai-Feng Fu / with an introduction by Prof. Cecil Roth, 1967., 22 cm. Text only.
    - Haggadah and woodcut: an introduction to the Passover Haggadah completed by Gershom Cohen in Prague, Sunday, 26 Teveth, 5287--Dec. 30, 1526 / by Rabbi Charles Wengrov, 1967., 29 cm. Illustrated.
      Published to accompany its facsimile edition.
    - Haggada for Passover = Hagadah / published in enlarged Hebrew and English type for the partially sighted for the Women's Branch of the Union of Orthodox Jewish Congregations of America and the Jewish Braille Institute of America, Inc. ...; newly translated throughout, with an introduction, by Harold Fisch, 1967., 38 cm. Text only.
    - Hagadat Bene Yisra'el = The Haggadah of the Bene Israel of India, 1968., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew and Marathi. Reproduction (partially reduced) of Bombay, 1846 ed.(Yaari no. 656) with added prefatory material by Walter J. Fischel and others. Original was the first Hebrew book printed in India with illustrations.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Haggadah of Passover / translation: A. Regelson; illustration: S. Forst, 1968., 15 cm. Illustrated.
      Haggadah printed by the Carmel wine company. In addition to the traditional seder in both Hebrew and English, this Haggadah contains advertisements for the full line of Carmel wines, liquors and champagnes. At the back of the Haggadah are suggestions for how to serve Carmel€™s different products as well suggestions for Passover cocktails and how to cook with Carmel products.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Hagadat Yerushalayim / nikhtevah ve-tsuyerah bi-yede Shemu'el Boneh, 1968., 31 cm. Illuminated.
      Location: Haifa, Israel
      Hebrew only. Illuminated by Shmuel Bonneh
    - The Passover Haggadah: with English translation, introduction, and commentary based on the commentaries of E.D. Goldschmidt / edited by Nahum N. Glatzer, 1969., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Translation of the Haggadah text by Jacob Sloan.
    - The Passover Haggadah: with English translation, introduction, and commentary based on the commentaries of E.D. Goldschmidt / edited by Nahum N. Glatzer, 1969., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Seder lel Pesah, 196-?., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew only. Published by Eliez Winecellars as an advertising tool for their brand of wines. Different advertisements for their wines appear throughout at the bottom pages.
    - The Passover Haggadah / illustrated by children of the arts and crafts classes of the General Israel Orphan's Home in Jerusalem; with a guide for the Seder, 196-?., 16 cm. Illustrated.
      Published as a fundraising tool for the General Israel Orphan's Home in Jerusalem.
  - 1970-1979 Subseries, (40 items)
    - Exhibit: Haggadahs and Passover ceremonial art, April-June, 1970, 1970., 23 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Waltham, Massachussetts
      Program for an exhibit of Haggadot and Passover ceremonial art at the American Jewish Historical Society. Introductions by Dr. Cecil Roth and Abram Kanof, M.D. Duke has two copies of this Haggadah.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = 4th-World Haggadah: with commentary / compiled by Joel Harris; edited and new English translation by Jack Schuldenfrei, 1970., 23 cm. Illustrated.
      Duke has two copies of this Haggadah.
    - [Hagadah shel Pesah] = An archaeological Passover Haggadah / newly-translated by Cecil Roth; edited by Beno Rothenberg; introduction by Michael Avi-Yonah, 1970., 31 cm. Illustrated.
    - An Israel Haggadah for Passover. Adapted by Meyer Levin, 1970., 29 cm. Illustrated.
      The aim in this Haggadah has been to include the beautiful and unforgettable utterances of tradition in an adaptation that will make the seder more pertinent to many who had come to regard it as rote€ --p. 13. Includes photographs of modern Israeli scenes. Handwritten notes in English throughout c.2.
    - An Israel Haggadah for Passover / adapted by Meyer Levin, 1970., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Includes music.
    - The freedom seder; a new Haggadah for Passover, by Arthur I. Waskow, 1970., 19 cm. Illustrated.
      Freedom Seder was first used on April 4, 1969, the first anniversary of [Dr. Martin Luther] King's death and the third night of Passover by 300 'Jews for Urban Justice' and 100 Christians -The Shalom Seders, pg. 8.
    - Hagadah le-Pesah Me-`avdut le-herut, 1970-71., 30 x 16 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Givatayim, Israel
      Modern Israeli Haggadah, put out by the Israeli Defense Force, adds to the traditional story of redemption from Egypt new chapters which tell of the miracles experienced during the creation of the modern state of Israel. The traditional text of the seder appears on the top of each page with new parallels stories from the modern day in smaller print at the bottom of each page. For example, below the traditional four questions are four different questions pointing out the differences between seders of old and modern seders. The first new question points out that in the olden days Jews celebrated Israel leaving Egypt, while in modern days Jews also celebrate Egyptians leaving Israel. The haggadah is illustrated with photographs and illustrations of the Israeli army an other modern Israeli scenes.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah = The Tel Aviv Haggadah: first printed edition of an 18th Century illuminated handwritten Haggadah with an abridged version of Don Isaac Abarbanel's Commentary, 1771 .., 1971., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Yiddish and Hebrew. Preface signed by Tovia Preschel.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah = The Tel Aviv Haggadah: first printed edition of an 18th Century illuminated handwritten Haggadah with an abridged version of Don Isaac Abarbanel's Commentary, 1771 .., 1971., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - The new model Seder / edited by Rabbi Sidney Greenberg and S. Allan Sugarman, 1971., 25 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Bridgeport, Connecticut
      Includes supplementary English readings, including Dr. Martin Luther King's I Have a Dream speech.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah = The Tel Aviv Haggadah: first printed edition of an 18th Century illuminated handwritten Haggadah with an abridged version of Don Isaac Abarbanel's Commentary, 1771 .., 1971., 21 cm. Illustrated.
    - Let my people go: a Haggadah. / illustrated by Mark Podwal; introduction by Theodore Bikel, 1972., 29 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Signed by the author. Hebrew and English text; reads from left to right. Illustrations are based on the plight of Soviet Jews.
    - Hagadah li-yeladim = The children's Haggadah / edited by A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Erwin Singer with a new translation in prose and verse by Isidore Wartski and Rev. Saul Super, 1972., 29 cm. Illustrated.
      English and Hebrew. Some ill. have movable parts.
    - A feast of history; Passover through the ages as a key to Jewish experience. With a new translation of the Haggadah for use at the Seder. [Photos. by David Harris], 1972., 25 cm. Illustrated.
      Text of Hagadah (p. 158-250) in Hebrew and English. Includes 157 pages on the history of Passover and the Haggadah.
    - The Passover meal; a ritual for Christian homes, 1972., 17 cm. Illustrated.
      English only.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah bi-leshon ha-kodesh u-fitrono bi-leshon Italyano = The Venice Haggadah with Judeo-Italian translation, Venice 1609, 1973., 21 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew with Judeo-Italian translation. Original edition prepared by Leone da Modena. Introd. in English and Hebrew by T. Preschel.
    - Let my people go: a Haggadah / Illustrated by Mark Podwal. Foreword by Abba Eban. Introd. by Theodore Bikel, 1973., 29 cm. Illustrated.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah nikhtevah ve-tsuyerah be-Nikelsburg bi- shenat 508 = The Passover Haggadah written and illustrated in Nickelsburg 1748, 1973., 30 cm. Illustrated.
      Text in Hebrew; rubrics in Hebrew and Yiddish. Facsimile of the manuscript of the Passover Haggadah written and illustrated in Nickelsburg in 1748.
    - A Passover Haggadah; the new Union Haggadah edited by Herbert Bronstein for the Central Conference of American Rabbis. Drawings by Leonard Baskin, 1974., 37 cm. Illustrated.
      Edited by The Central Conference of American Rabbis, the rabbinic association for Reform Judaism. Combines the traditional seder service - in both Hebrew and English - with commentary written throughout Jewish history. -Inside flap of dust jacket.
    - Polychrome historical Haggadah for Passover = [Hagadah "Me'ir `enayim"] / with a commentary, interpretative translation, introduction, notes, references, and bibliography, by Jacob Freedman, D.D.; and illustrations in color from rare medieval Haggadah manuscripts, 1974., 29 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: Springfield, Massachussetts
      Text is colored according to when it was written. Bookmark, with keys to colors and symbols, inserted. Bibliography: p. 129-130.
    - A Passover Haggadah / drawings by Leonard Baskin; Central Conference of American Rabbis, 1974., 26 cm. Illustrated.
      The New Union Haggadah prepared by the Central Conference of American Rabbis.-- Cover. ebrew and/or English. Unacc. melodies (Hebrew text romanized): p. 97-122.
    - A Passover Haggadah; the new Union Haggadah edited by Herbert Bronstein for the Central Conference of American Rabbis. Drawings by Leonard Baskin, 1974., 37 cm. Illustrated.
    - Haggadah and history: a panorama in facsimile of five centuries of the printed Haggadah from the collections of Harvard University and the Jewish Theological Seminary of America / by Yosef Hayim Yerushalmi, 1975., Illustrated.
      Location: Philadelphia
      History of the printed Haggadah with illustrations and descriptions of a representative selection.
    - A Passover Haggadah: the new Union Haggadah / edited by Herbert Bronstein; drawings by Leonard Baskin, 1975., 26 cm. Illustrated.
      Edited by The Central Conference of American Rabbis, the rabbinic association for Reform Judaism. Includes music.
    - The Passover Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah: with a modern translation, explanatory notes, historical background, and new readings / compiled and edited by Rabbi Morris Silverman; designed and illustrated by Ezekiel Schloss, 1975., 24 cm. Illustrated.
      Traditional text with contemporary readings for Russian Jewry, in memory of the Holocaust, etc.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah = The Kittsee Haggadah: first printed edition of an 18th Century illuminated handwritten Haggadah, 1782 .., 1975., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Yiddish and Hebrew. A reproductin of the The Kittsee Haggadah of 1782 for fundraising purposes.
    - The Haggadah of Passover / illustrations by Parenzo; text edited by Rabbi David and Tamar de Sola Pool, 1975., 25 cm. Illustrated.
      Location: New Jersey
    - Passover Hagadah / illustrated with the commentary of Rabbi Dr. Marcus Lehmann of Mainz, rendered into English for the first time, 1975., 26 cm. Illustrated.
      Hebrew text of Hagadah with English translation and commentary.
    - Haggadah and history: a panorama in facsimile of five centuries of the printed Haggadah from the collections of Harvard University and the Jewish Theological Seminary of America / by Yosef Hayim Yerushalmi, 1975., Illustrated.
    - Hagadah seder shel Pesah = The Fuerth haggadah, 1976., 22 cm. Illustrated.
      Text in Judeo-German. Introduction in English and Hebrew by Tovia Preschel. Facsimile reproduction of the Fuerth haggadah, published in 1741.
    - The Birnbaum Haggadah / [translation and commentary by] Philip Birnbaum, 1976., 24 cm. Illustrated.
      Text in English and Hebrew.
    - A Christian Seder / by James G. Emerson, Jr, 1976., 23 cm. Text only.
      Location: Denver, Colorado
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah = The Leipnik-Rosenthaliana Haggadah, 1977., 21 cm. Illustrated.